# Michael Takeuchi

Phoenix, AZ 85016 | 310-256-8272 | mikemtaki@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> |

### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Web developer with knowledge in Ruby and Javascript frameworks. Transitioning from sales, I bring strong communication skills, from experience collaborating with a team and clients. I have prioritized tasks to meet deadlines and hit KPIs, to align with manager's goals.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, and React

### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Boon - Github | Demo

Stock tracker to record stock transactions, and view total returns and market value of portfolio.

- Developed full Ruby on Rails web app.
- Utilized Devise gem and Omniauth for user authentication and the ability to sign in with Google account.
- Programmed portfolio to showcase individuals profits and equity, along with the categories they
  are invested in.

## Apricus - Github | Demo

Wine journal to document wine profiles.

- Designed Rails API backend with wine and reviews models.
- Implemented Javascript frontend with Bootstrap styling.
- Developed search filter to give users access to view only select wines by name.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Southern Glazer's Wine & Spirits

Torrance, CA

Chain Sales Merchandiser

05/2016 - 03/2020

- Sold in monthly planner products for 24 consecutive months from 2018-2020.
- Built displays in 50% of accounts that helped buyers reduce inventory and increased sales during Q4 in 2019.
- Helped 5 new accounts organize wine and liquor department plans during grand openings.

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/2020 - 10/2020

University of California, Davis Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Economics Davis, CA

06/2015